# **Andy Hotzler**

Bemidji, MN 56601 || (218) 368-0302

Portfolio | ahotzler@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/andyhotzler

## **Professional Summary:**

Quality assurance tester, problem-solver, tinkerer, software engineer, and passionate gamer. Experience troubleshooting software on PC, Steam, and PS4. Comfortable communicating opinions and feedback with all departments. Proficient with Jira and proven to be effective learning new tools quickly. Excellent verbal and written communication skills coupled with solid time management and organizational skills. Team-oriented but can also work autonomously.

Ready to relocate and work atypical hours.

### **Skills Summary:**

- 10 months experience in quality assurance testing
- Experience across the entire software test cycle process
- Proficient with MS Office, Jira, JavaScript, and software testing frameworks
- Able to read/write technical documentation
- Foundational game design knowledge
- Great interpersonal/conflict resolution skills
- Deadline driven with keen attention to detail
- Passionate about Naughty Dog and its IPs

## **Relevant Experience:**

Software Engineer (Certificate) Thinkful, Remote, US

**December 2020 – May 2021** 

- Built full-stack applications, databases, and wrote software test cases.
- Practiced best quality assurance testing techniques to ensure full functionality and intended usability.
- Led group projects, delegating tasks for large projects to four co-learners, and tracked bugs and tasks with Kanban boards.

# Graduate Teaching Associate/Adjunct Instructor August 2013 - December 2017 Bemidji State University, Bemidji, MN, US

- (NOTE: Left position/program due to terminally-ill parent).
- Created course syllabus, lecture plans, assignments, and generated feedback on student papers in accordance with curriculum requirements.
- Remained flexible and adaptive in order to change lectures based on students' strengths and weaknesses.
- Grading papers was analogous to regression testing.

#### Web Publishing/QA Internship Heroic Age, Bemidji State University

August 2011 – December 2011

- Checked website for broken links, replacing with correct URLs when necessary.
- Proofread for grammatical/spelling errors, as well as missing alt text for images.

#### **Education:**

## **Bemidji State University**

May 2013

Bachelor of Arts, English

Awarded scholarship as top student in the B.A. program.

**Bachelor of Fine Arts, Professional/Creative Writing** 

Awarded scholarship for creative work and recognition as top student in B.F.A. program.

**Bachelor of Arts, Humanities** 

Emphasis in German studies. Minor in Philosophy.

### **Certificates:**

GameDev.TV September 2021

**C++ Fundamentals: Game Programming for Beginners, Online** 

Built three projects with increasing difficulty in vanilla C++ using Raylib library.

University of British Columbia Expected Completion: October 2021 Video Game Writing Essentials, Online, EdX

First course of six. Analyzed game narratives/design and wrote design documents.

Harvard University Expected Completion: December 2021 Intro to Computer Science, Online, EdX

Studied computing/hardware basics, and fundamental Python, C/C++, and A.I.